[
  {
    "question": "Cynology is the study of what?",
    "answer": "Dogs"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which country was Henry Kissinger born?",
    "answer": "Germany"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the work 'The Marriage of Figaro'?",
    "answer": "Mozart"
  },
  {
    "question": "Born Eric Arthur Blair in Motihari, Bengal, India, this famous author is better known by what pseudonym?",
    "answer": "George Orwell"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Roman mythology, who was the king of the gods?",
    "answer": "Jupiter"
  },
  {
    "question": "A cow's stomach is divided into how many compartments?",
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term for cutting vegetables into long thin matchstick like shapes?",
    "answer": "Julienne"
  },
  {
    "question": "Known as 'The Mile High' city, what is the capital city of Colorado",
    "answer": "Denver"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the sitcom Dad's Army Arnold Ridley played which character?",
    "answer": "Private Godfrey"
  },
  {
    "question": "Indira Gandhi International Airport services which city?",
    "answer": "Delhi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Born Leonardo Bonacci in Pisa, Italy, which mathematician identified a sequence where the following number is made by adding the two previous number?",
    "answer": "Fibonacci"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which traditional Royal Navy term refers to a day or shorter period reserved for rest and recovery?",
    "answer": "Banyan"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Pascal is the SI unit for measuring what?",
    "answer": "Pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nation won the 2014 World Cup?",
    "answer": "Germany"
  },
  {
    "question": "The M55 motorway links the M6 north of Preston to which seaside town?",
    "answer": "Blackpool"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British city is affectionately known as 'Brizzle'?",
    "answer": "Bristol"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which was the film Grease released to cinemas? \na) 1978 \nb) 1972 \nc) 1982",
    "answer": "1978"
  }
]
